Michael Alpert collection
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
- Series 6: Eastern Europe field recordings
  Field recordings from Michael Alpert's fieldwork in Eastern Europe, primarily Romania and Ukraine. Included are interviews and conversations with performers, social gatherings, special events and celebrations, other performances, and music in monasteries.
  - Vashkivitsi, Ukraine, July 28, 2001, AFC 2017/048: SR0096; Personnel: Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Vashkivitsi, Ukraine.; Alpert 172-173; 1 sound cassette
  - Russian Soviet Jewish- II, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0139; Personnel: Michael Alpert.; Alpert 240-241; 1 sound cassette
  - Soviet Jewish- III, April 10-May 14, 1982, AFC 2017/048: SR0140; Personnel: Zyama Epshteyn, Rakhel Datkashvili, Fanya Moshinskaya, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Singer's home.; Alpert 242-243; 1 sound cassette
  - Zyama Epshteyn; Fanya Moshinskaya, May 4, 1982, AFC 2017/048: SR0142; Personnel, Side A: Zyama Epshteyn, Michael Alpert. Personnel, Side B: Fanya Moshinskaya, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 246-247; 1 sound cassette
  - Ukraine, Romania, 2001, afc2017048_dc001; Personnel: Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Ukraine, Romania.; Alpert 259; 1 WAV
  - Wedding in Poland, May 10, 2003, afc2017048_dc001; Recording location: Nowy Targ, Poland.; Alpert 277; 1 WAV
  - Klezshul 2005 I, 2005, afc2017048_dc001; Personnel: Michael Alpert.; Alpert 294; 1 WAV
  - Klezshul 2005 II, 2005, afc2017048_dc001; Personnel: Michael Alpert.; Alpert 295; 1 WAV
  - Ashkenaz, September 2, 2006, afc2017048_dc001; Personnel: Michael Alpert.; Alpert 298; 1 WAV
  - Iosif Ganberg, February 28, 2007, afc2017048_dc001; Personnel: Iosif Ganberg.; Alpert 301; 1 WAV
  - Iosif Ganberg, March 2, 2007, afc2017048_dc001; Personnel: Iosif Ganberg.; Alpert 302; 1 WAV
  - Zelig and Riva Kovnater, March 3, 2007, afc2017048_dc001; Personnel: Zelig and Riva Kovnater.; Alpert 305; 1 WAV
  - Nachman Teitelbaum, April 7, 1982, AFC 2017/048: SR0163; Personnel: Makheteneste (Deg) - Itsik Mitn Fidl (Deg)- Lomir Ale In Eynem.; Alpert 307-308; 1 sound cassette
  - Zyama Epshteyn, Maya Yudelson; Maya Yudelson, April 10, 1982, AFC 2017/048: SR0164; Personnel, Side A: Zyama Epshteyn, Maya Yudelson, Michael Alpert. Personnel, Side B: Nachman Teitelbaum, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 310-311; 1 sound cassette
  - Isaak Varshavsky, October 15, 1982, AFC 2017/048: SR0165; Personnel: Isaak Varshavsky, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 312-313; 1 sound cassette
  - Volodia-Nano I, August 1, 2001, afc2017048_dc001; Personnel: Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Vashkivitsi, Ukraine.; Alpert 314; 1 WAV
  - Vodolia-Nano II, August 1, 2001, afc2017048_dc001; Personnel: Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Vashkivitsi, Ukraine.; Alpert 315; 1 WAV
  - Vodolia-Nano III, August 1, 2001, afc2017048_dc001; Personnel: Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Vashkivitsi, Ukraine.; Alpert 316; 1 WAV
  - Vashkivitsi, Volodia, undated, afc2017048_dc001; Personnel: Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Vashkivitsi, Ukraine.; Alpert 317; 1 WAV
  - Vashkivitsi, Volodia, Kheifets, Luchik, undated, afc2017048_dc001; Personnel: Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Vashkivitsi, Ukraine.; Alpert 322; 1 WAV
  - Vashkivitsi, Molev, Vinnitsai, undated, afc2017048_dc001; Personnel: Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Vashkivitsi, Ukraine.; Alpert 323; 1 WAV
  - Esther Kopit, May 24, 1988, AFC 2017/048: SR0167; Personnel: Esther Kopit, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 324; 1 sound cassette
  - Vashkivitsi Arrival, undated, afc2017048_dc001; Personnel: Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Vashkivitsi, Ukraine.; Alpert 325; 1 WAV
  - Vashkivitsi Wedding, undated, afc2017048_dc001; Personnel: Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Vashkivitsi, Ukraine.; Alpert 326; 1 WAV
  - Vashkivitsi Wedding End, undated, afc2017048_dc001; Personnel: Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Vashkivitsi, Ukraine.; Alpert 327; 1 WAV
  - Vashkivitsi Wedding I, undated, afc2017048_dc001; Personnel: Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Vashkivitsi, Ukraine.; Alpert 328; 1 WAV
  - Vashkivitsi Wedding II, undated, afc2017048_dc001; Personnel: Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Vashkivitsi, Ukraine.; Alpert 329; 1 WAV
  - Vashkivitsi Wedding III, undated, afc2017048_dc001; Personnel: Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Vashkivitsi, Ukraine.; Alpert 330; 1 WAV
  - Vashkivitsi Wedding End, undated, afc2017048_dc001; Personnel: Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Vashkivitsi, Ukraine.; Alpert 331; 1 WAV
  - Vashkivitsi Leaving, undated, afc2017048_dc001; Personnel: Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Vashkivitsi, Ukraine.; Alpert 332; 1 WAV
  - Mott Horowitz, May 24, 1988, AFC 2017/048: SR0168; Personnel: Mott Horowitz, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 333-334; 1 sound cassette
  - Meir Rabranvsky, Rafael and Bazia Zavelion- I, May 27, 1988, AFC 2017/048: SR0174; Personnel: Meir Rabranvsky,Rafael Zavelion, Bazia Zavelion, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 343-344; 1 sound cassette
  - Rafael and Bazia Zavelion- II; Yacov and Lyuba Feigin, May 27, 1988, AFC 2017/048: SR0175; Personnel: Meir Rabranvsky, Rafael Zavelion, Bazia Zavelion, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 345-346; 1 sound cassette
  - Chernivtsi "Salesmen's Day" Banquet, undated, afc2017048_dc001; Personnel: Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Chernivtsi.; Alpert 347; 1 WAV
  - Ukraine, Romania II, 2001, afc2017048_dc001; Personnel: Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Romania, Ukraine.; Alpert 348; 1 WAV
  - Vizhnitz- I, undated, afc2017048_dc001; Personnel: Elena Ivanivna Luchik, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 353; 1 WAV
  - Vizhnitz- Luchik and Hunchak, undated, afc2017048_dc001; Personnel: Elena Ivanivna Luchik, Hunchak, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 354; 1 WAV
  - Vizhnitz- Luchik and Slav'ko, undated, afc2017048_dc001; Personnel: Elena Ivanivna Luchik, Slav'ko, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 355; 1 WAV
  - Vizhnitz, undated, afc2017048_dc001; Personnel: Michael Alpert.; Alpert 356; 1 WAV
  - Rafael and Bazia Zavelion, August 24, 1988, AFC 2017/048: SR0182; Personnel: Rafael Zavelion, Bazia Zavelion, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 365-366; 1 sound cassette
  - Strauss Warschauer Duo, October 20, 2003, afc2017048_dc001; Personnel: Jeff Warschauer, Deborah Strauss, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 372; 1 WAV
  - Katya Kol'tsov, undated, afc2017048_dc001; Personnel: Katya Kol'tsov, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 375; 1 WAV
  - Sylwii Babcia, undated, afc2017048_dc001; Personnel: Sylwii Babcia, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 376; 1 WAV
  - Yanker Schaefer, August 25, 1988, AFC 2017/048: SR0186; Personnel: Yanker Schaefer, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 377; 1 sound cassette
  - Lyudmila Lantsman, August 26, 1988, AFC 2017/048: SR0187; Personnel: Lyudmila Lantsman, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 378; 1 sound cassette
  - Georgian Wedding I, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0195; Alpert 391-392; 1 sound cassette
  - Georgian Wedding II, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0196; Alpert 393-394; 1 sound cassette
  - Georgian, February 24, 1983, AFC 2017/048: SR0198; Recording location: Roza/Soso's; Alpert 396-397; 1 sound cassette
  - Yidl Aslavinsky, Rakhmiel Bilinson, June 1988, AFC 2017/048: SR0202; Personnel: Yidl Aslavinsky, Rakhmiel Bilinson.; Alpert 404-405; 1 sound cassette
  - Rakhmiel Bilinson- I, May 31, 1999, AFC 2017/048: SR0203; Personnel: Rakhmiel Bilinson, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 406-407; 1 sound cassette
  - Rakhmiel Bilinson- I (Copy), May 31, 1999, AFC 2017/048: SR0671; Personnel: Rakhmiel Bilinson, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 406-407; 1 sound cassette
  - Rakhmiel Bilinson- II, May 31, 1999, AFC 2017/048: SR0204; Personnel: Rakhmiel Bilinson, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 408-409; 1 sound cassette
  - Rakhmiel Bilinson- II (Copy), May 31, 1999, AFC 2017/048: SR0672; Personnel: Rakhmiel Bilinson, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 408-409; 1 sound cassette
  - Rakhmiel Bilinson- III, May 31, 1999, AFC 2017/048: SR0211; Personnel: Rakhmiel Bilinson, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 410-411; 1 sound cassette
  - Rakhmiel Bilinson- III (Copy), May 31, 1999, AFC 2017/048: SR0673; Personnel: Rakhmiel Bilinson, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 410-411; 1 sound cassette
  - Rakhmiel Bilinson- IV, May 31, 1999, AFC 2017/048: SR0205; Personnel: Rakhmiel Bilinson, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 412-413; 1 sound cassette
  - Rakhmiel Bilinson- IV (Copy), May 31, 1999, AFC 2017/048: SR0674; Personnel: Rakhmiel Bilinson, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 412-413; 1 sound cassette
  - Modzhitz, August 22-27, 1988, AFC 2017/048: SR0208; Alpert 419-420; 1 sound cassette
  - Semyon Kofman- I, June 23, 1997, AFC 2017/048: SR0229; Personnel: Semyon Kofman, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 454-455; 1 sound cassette
  - L'viw, November 1, 1990, AFC 2017/048: SR0234; Recording location: L'viw.; Alpert 463-464; 1 sound cassette
  - L'viw- III, November 1, 1990, AFC 2017/048: SR0235; Personnel: Meylekh Sheykher, Oksana Halyova, Pavlo Laskin, Arkady, Sandler Avrom.; Recording location: L'viw/car.; Alpert 465-466; 1 sound cassette
  - L'viw- IV, November 1, 1990, AFC 2017/048: SR0236; Personnel: Avrum Zaharovid Sandler, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: L'viw.; Alpert 467; 1 sound cassette
  - L'viw - V, November 1, 1990, AFC 2017/048: SR0237; Personnel: Reb Ausya Shtinman, Meylekh Sheykher, Avrohom Rosenthal.; Recording location: L'viw.; Alpert 468-469; 1 sound cassette
  - Bushtyna, Munkacs, November 4, 1990, AFC 2017/048: SR0238; Personnel: Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Bushtyna-Munkacs.; Alpert 470; 1 sound cassette
  - Max; Car to Uzhgorod, November 1990, AFC 2017/048: SR0239; Personnel: Max, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 471-472; 1 sound cassette
  - Khust, November 1990, AFC 2017/048: SR0240; Recording location: Khust.; Alpert 473-474; 1 sound cassette
  - Khust- I, November 1990, AFC 2017/048: SR0241; Personnel: Dina, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Khust.; Alpert 475-476; 1 sound cassette
  - East Europe Trip - IV, 1990, AFC 2017/048: SR0242; Personnel: Michael Alpert, Joel Rubin.; Recording location: Train Praha-Berlin.; Alpert 477-478; 1 sound cassette
  - Maximilian, USSR Trip, October-November, 1990, AFC 2017/048: SR0243; Personnel: Michael Alpert, Maximilian.; Recording location: Train and car.; Alpert 479-480; 1 sound cassette
  - Leopold Kozlowski, October 12, 1990, AFC 2017/048: SR0245; Personnel: Leopold Kozlowski, Michael Alpert, Joel Rubin.; Recording location: Krakow, Poland.; Alpert 483-484; 1 sound cassette
  - Leopold Kozlowski- II, October 12, 1990, AFC 2017/048: SR0246; Personnel: Leopold Kozlowski, Michael Alpert, Joel Rubin.; Recording location: Krakow, Poland.; Alpert 485-486; 1 sound cassette
  - Leopold Kozlowski- III, October 12, 1990, AFC 2017/048: SR0247; Personnel: Leopold Kozlowski, Michael Alpert, Joel Rubin.; Recording location: Krakow, Poland.; Alpert 487-488; 1 sound cassette
  - Michael Alpert on Radio Krakow, October 5, 2003, AFC 2017/048: SR0271; Personnel: Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Radio Krakow.; Alpert 545; 1 sound cassette
  - Sonya Kruger, Lodz Ghetto, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0274; Personnel: Sonya Kruger, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 549-550; 1 sound cassette
  - Itzik Schwarz- I, December 31, 1998, AFC 2017/048: SR0275; Personnel: Itzik Schwarz, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Iaşi, Romania.; Alpert 551-552; 1 sound cassette
  - Itzik Schwarz- II, December 31, 1998, AFC 2017/048: SR0276; Personnel: Itzik Schwarz, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Iaşi, Romania.; Alpert 553-554; 1 sound cassette
  - Itzik Schwarz- III, January 1, 1999, AFC 2017/048: SR0277; Personnel: Itzik Schwarz, Michael Alpert, Francesco Spagnolo.; Recording location: Iaşi, Romania.; Alpert 555; 1 sound cassette
  - Itzik Schwarz- IV, January 1, 1999, AFC 2017/048: SR0278; Personnel: Itzik Schwarz, Michael Alpert, Francesco Spagnolo.; Recording location: Iaşi, Romania.; Alpert 556-557; 1 sound cassette
  - Iasi- I, December 1998-January 1999, AFC 2017/048: SR0279; Personnel: Michael Alpert, Francesco Spagnolo.; Recording location: Iaşi, Romania.; Alpert 558-559; 1 sound cassette
  - Iasi, January 3, 1999, AFC 2017/048: SR0280; Personnel: Michael Alpert, Francesco Spagnolo, Izrael Ide.; Recording location: Iaşi, Romania.; Alpert 560-561; 1 sound cassette
  - Iasi, January 2-3, 1999, AFC 2017/048: SR0281; Personnel: Michael Alpert, Francesco Spagnolo.; Recording location: Iaşi, Romania.; Alpert 562-563; 1 sound cassette
  - Majer Bogdanski- I, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0282; Personnel: Majer Bogdanski.; Alpert 564-565; 1 sound cassette
  - Majer Bogdanski- II, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0283; Personnel: Majer Bogdanski.; Alpert 566; 1 sound cassette
  - Yankl Gorelick- I, May 29, 1986, AFC 2017/048: SR0284; Personnel: Yankl Gorelick, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 567-568; 1 sound cassette
  - Yankl Gorelick- II, May 29, 1986, AFC 2017/048: SR0285; Personnel: Yankl Gorelick, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 569-570; 1 sound cassette
  - Yankl Gorelick, August 18, 1986, AFC 2017/048: SR0286; Personnel: Yankl Gorelick, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 571-572; 1 sound cassette
  - Izu Gott plays ER Bughic's book, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0288; Personnel: Izu Gott.; Alpert 575-576; 1 sound cassette
  - MM Shaffir and Birnboym, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0294; Personnel: M.M. Shaffir, Martin Birnboym.; Alpert 585; 1 sound cassette
  - Golde Hochman, January 22, 1985, AFC 2017/048: SR0322; Personnel: Golde Hochman.; Alpert 633-634; 1 sound cassette
  - Rumanian Lodge-Bnai Zion Purim Ball, March 23, 1986, AFC 2017/048: SR0327; Alpert 641-642; 1 sound cassette
  - Toyvye Birnboym, July 11, 1986, AFC 2017/048: SR0329; Personnel: Toyvye Birnboym.; Alpert 645-646; 1 sound cassette
  - Zoltan Breban-I, 1985, AFC 2017/048: SR0330; Personnel: Zoltan Breban.; Alpert 647-648; 1 sound cassette
  - Zoltan Breban-II, 1985, AFC 2017/048: SR0331; Personnel: Zoltan Breban.; Alpert 649; 1 sound cassette
  - Leopold Kozlowski, June 3, 1991, AFC 2017/048: SR0338; Personnel: Leopold Kozlowski, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 661-662; 1 sound cassette
  - Bobov; Bobov and Munkatsh, September 24, 1994, AFC 2017/048: SR0346; Personnel: Michael Alpert, Mark Kligman.; Recording location: Bobov.; Alpert 674-675; 1 sound cassette
  - Meir (Mayer) Bogdanski, July 29, 1998, AFC 2017/048: SR0351; Personnel: Meir (Mayer) Bogdanski.; Alpert 683-684; 1 sound cassette
  - Lajb Cala-I, March 11, 1999, AFC 2017/048: SR0352; Personnel: Lajb Cala, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 685-686; 1 sound cassette
  - Lajb Cala-II, March 11, 1999, AFC 2017/048: SR0353; Personnel: Lajb Cala, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 687-688; 1 sound cassette
  - Narocki, July 1, 1999, AFC 2017/048: SR0354; Personnel: Narocki.; Recording location: Krakow.; Alpert 689-690; 1 sound cassette
  - Yidl Finkel-I, July 2, 1999, AFC 2017/048: SR0355; Personnel: Yidl Finkel, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Krakow.; Alpert 691-692; 1 sound cassette
  - Yidl Finkel-II, July 2, 1999, AFC 2017/048: SR0356; Personnel: Yidl Finkel, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Krakow.; Alpert 693-694; 1 sound cassette
  - RadioSofia; Croation-Serbian Radio, 1968, July 1977, AFC 2017/048: SR0360; Alpert 701; 1 sound cassette
  - Wernisaz Concert, June 2001, AFC 2017/048: SR0361; Personnel: Jeff Warschauer, Deborah Strauss, Stuart Brotman, David Krakauer, Michael Steinlauf, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Tratwa Muzykantow "The Musicans' Raft", Centrum Pogranicze (The Borderlands Center for Arts, Cultures and Peoples), Sejny, Poland.; Alpert 704-705; 1 sound cassette
  - Yaacov Rotenberg-Songs from Lodz, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0364; Personnel: Yaacov Rotenberg.; Recording location: Tel Aviv, Israel.; Alpert 709; 1 sound cassette
  - Yaacov Rotenberg, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0365; Personnel: Yaacov Rotenberg.; Alpert 710; 1 sound cassette
  - Greek Jewish Musical Tradition, 1984, AFC 2017/048: SR0381; Personnel: Joe Elias.; Alpert 734-735; 1 sound cassette
  - Sephardim Turkey-I; Sephardim Turkey-II, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0383; Alpert 738-739; 1 sound cassette
  - Arkady Gendler, March 20, 2000, AFC 2017/048: SR0385; Personnel: Arkady Gendler.; Alpert 742; 1 sound cassette
  - Yehuda Abubolul-II, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0386; Personnel: Yehuda Abubolul, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 743; 1 sound cassette
  - Balkan-Bertha Kling, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0387; Personnel: Bertha Kling.; Alpert 744-745; 1 sound cassette
  - Liza Khorunzhaya, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0388; Personnel: Liza Khorunzhaya, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 746-747; 1 sound cassette
  - Yaacov Rotenberg, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0390; Personnel: Yaacov Rotenberg.; Recording location: Tel Aviv.; Alpert 750; 1 sound cassette
  - German Radio Program, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0409; Alpert 780-781; 1 sound cassette
  - Rokeri's Moravu, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0412; Personnel: Rokeri's Moravu.; Alpert 786; 1 sound cassette
  - Smyrnaika, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0413; Alpert 787-788; 1 sound cassette
  - Chassidic Marches, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0414; Alpert 789; 1 sound cassette
  - Tratwa Muzykantow; Majer Bogdanski, June-August 2001, AFC 2017/048: SR0419; Personnel: Deborah Strauss, Jeff Warschauer, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Sejny, Poland.; Alpert 796-797; 1 sound cassette
  - YIVO Ukrainian Russian-Jewish 78s, May 1998, AFC 2017/048: SR0425; Alpert 807; 1 sound cassette
  - Nightlosers, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0427; Alpert 810-811; 1 sound cassette
  - Hungarian-Jewish Fiddlers (Bob Cohen), August 1992, AFC 2017/048: SR0428; Alpert 812-813; 1 sound cassette
  - Romania from Bob, Christina, John, and Fumi, 2000, AFC 2017/048: SR0429; Personnel: Bob Cohen, Christina Crowder, John Demetryk, Fumi Suzuki.; Alpert 814-815; 1 sound cassette
  - Simkhes Toyre, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0431; Alpert 818-819; 1 sound cassette
  - Transylvanian Jewish Songs, Gypsy Songs, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0433; Personnel: Transylvanian Jewish Man.; Alpert 822-823; 1 sound cassette
  - Martin Gyorgy; Karpatlja Ruthenia, Czernowitz Jewish, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0435; Personnel: Martin Gyorgy.; Recording location: Satmar.; Alpert 825-826; 1 sound cassette
  - Szatmar, Transylvanian, and Trans Carpathian Fiddlers play Jewish Tunes; E Europe Recollections Part V, 1990, AFC 2017/048: SR0436; Alpert 827-828; 1 sound cassette
  - Ciganska Krv-Romano Rat; Zupkovich Memorial, Balkan BLP 5011, Dunav, BLP 5007, July 1, 1987, AFC 2017/048: SR0444; Personnel: Ansambl Jovice Nikolića.; Alpert 841-842; 1 sound cassette
  - Kold Nidre in Moscow, 1956, AFC 2017/048: SR0453; Recording location: Moscow.; Alpert 857-858; 1 sound cassette
  - Borekh Schwartz-II, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0489; Alpert 939-940; 1 sound cassette
  - Russian-Soviet Jewish Tape I, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0492; Personnel: Michael Alpert.; Alpert 944-945; 1 sound cassette
  - Arkady Gendler sings Yiddish, 1997, AFC 2017/048: SR0493; Personnel: Arkady Gendler.; Alpert 946; 1 sound cassette
  - Lea Levy and Cantor Louis Itkiss, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0495; Personnel: Lea Levy, Cantor Louis Itkiss.; Alpert 949-950; 1 sound cassette
  - Ram Hadad-Yehuda Abubolul, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0516; Alpert 988-989; 1 sound cassette
  - Unlabeled, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0518; Alpert 992; 1 sound cassette
  - Pola Thorne, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0520; Personnel: Pola Thorne.; Alpert 994; 1 sound cassette
  - Marlis and Cornelia; Pekka Gronow Tapes, August 31-September 1, 1983, 1983-09-01, AFC 2017/048: SR0521; Personnel: Marlis Kraft, Cornelia Kraft.; Alpert 995-996; 1 sound cassette
  - Luba Traub, 1989, AFC 2017/048: SR0523; Personnel: Luba Traub.; Alpert 998-999; 1 sound cassette
  - Kapelye London, July 8, 1984, AFC 2017/048: SR0526; Recording location: Intimate Theater, London, England.; Alpert 1004-1005; 1 sound cassette
  - SFB-Journal in 3 v, June 27, 1989, AFC 2017/048: SR0528; Recording location: Studiogespräch.; Alpert 1008; 1 sound cassette
  - Einstein-I, July 5, 1989, AFC 2017/048: SR0529; Recording location: Einstein.; Alpert 1009-1010; 1 sound cassette
  - Einstein-II, July 5, 1989, AFC 2017/048: SR0530; Recording location: Einstein.; Alpert 1011; 1 sound cassette
  - CKE Krakow 99, Yidl Frenkel, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0540; Alpert 1031-1032; 1 sound cassette
  - SKE Rehearsal Krakow-II, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0541; Alpert 1033-1034; 1 sound cassette
  - Arkady Gendler-I, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0548; Personnel: Arkady Gendler.; Alpert 1045; 1 minidisc
  - Arkady Gendler-II, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0549; Personnel: Arkady Gendler.; Alpert 1046; 1 minidisc
  - Arkady Gendler, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0550; Personnel: Arkady Gendler.; Alpert 1047; 1 minidisc
  - Lodz, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0553; Alpert 1050; 1 minidisc
  - Sylwia Prasniewska, June 21, 2004, AFC 2017/048: SR0557; Personnel: Sylwia Prasniewska, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Ciechanow.; Alpert 1054; 1 minidisc
  - Khevrisa's Wedding, October 20, 2001, AFC 2017/048: SR0603; Recording location: Florence.; Alpert 1108-1109; 1 sound cassette
  - The Ukrainian Brass Band from Vynnytsia, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0606; Alpert 1113-1114; 1 sound cassette
  - Jewish Keyboards of the USSR, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0611; Alpert 1123; 1 sound cassette
  - Karavan Work Tape, 1981, AFC 2017/048: SR0612; Alpert 1124-1125; 1 sound cassette
  - Zalman Schaechter, 1984, afc2017048_dc001; Alpert 1127; 1 WAV
  - Zalman Schaechter, 1984, afc2017048_dc001; Alpert 1128; 1 WAV
  - Zalman Schaechter, Bern University, 1984, AFC 2017/048: SR0620; Alpert 1140-1141; 1 sound cassette
  - My Guitar; Jugoslav, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0639; Alpert 1169-1170; 1 sound cassette (microcassette)
  - Digital surrogates of recordings in Series 6, 1956-2007, afc2017048_dc001; Digital copies of audio are available as both WAV and MP3 files. PDF files depicting the outside of each audio carrier are also available for many of the recordings.; 206 WAV, 206 MP3, 99 PDF
- Series 7: North American field recordings
  Field recordings from Michael Alpert's fieldwork in North America, primarily New York City and Los Angeles. Includes interviews and conversations with performers, social gatherings, special events and celebrations, and other performances.
  There are no digital surrogates for AFC 2017/048: SR0628 through SR0638.
  - Yosef Kagansky, July, 1999, AFC 2017/048: SR0113; Personnel: Yosef Kagansky.; Recording location: Boston.; Alpert 197; 1 sound cassette
  - JASA B-day Party; Fanya Moshinskaya- II, April 29-May 4, 1982, AFC 2017/048: SR0141; Personnel: Khaya Sherman, Lucy Bogomosky, Sonya Rabinovich, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Bronx.; Alpert 244-245; 1 sound cassette
  - David Krakauer, February 20, 2002, afc2017048_dc001; Personnel: David Krakauer, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Michael Alpert's house.; Alpert 262; 1 WAV
  - Beregovski's legacy lecture and demo, May 22, 2002, afc2017048_dc001; Personnel: James Loeffler, Mark Slobin, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Eldridge Street, NYC.; Alpert 263; 1 WAV
  - Night Songs I, Julian Kytasty, May 29, 2002, afc2017048_dc001; Personnel: Julian Kytasty, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Eldridge Street, NYC.; Alpert 268; 1 WAV
  - Night Songs II, Julian Kytasty, May 29, 2002, afc2017048_dc001; Personnel: Julian Kytasty, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Eldridge Street, NYC.; Alpert 269; 1 WAV
  - Bill Safran I, April 25, 2005, afc2017048_dc001; Personnel: Bill Safran, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 286; 1 WAV
  - Bill Safran II, April 25, 2005, afc2017048_dc001; Personnel: Bill Safran, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 287; 1 WAV
  - Zevulun Avshalomov, March 1981, AFC 2017/048: SR0160; Personnel: Zevulun Avshalomov, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 299-300; 1 sound cassette
  - Festival Performers Tape, July 25, 1982, AFC 2017/048: SR0161; Personnel: Iosif Glushkin, Tanya Lebedinskaya, Gennady Gutkin, Fanya Moshinskaya, Zyama Epshteyn, Semyon Kommisar, Borekh Shildergemeyn, Yeva Chornaya, Yefim Libovich, Khaya Sherman, Boris Legun.; Alpert 303-304; 1 sound cassette